Studer, Norman; Papers apap116
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Camp Woodland, 1938-2012; Undated; 4; 3.26 cubic ft.
  - Administration, 1938-1963; Undated; 4.1
    Of particular interest are the folders pertaining to the Larkin Committee's investigation of Norman Studer and Camp Woodland as having sympathetic ties with the Communist Party. During the early months of 1955, the Joint Legislative Committee on Charitable and Philanthropic Agencies and Organizations of New York (also known as the Larkin Committee after Committee Head State Senator Edward Larkin) investigated the possibility of subversive training and indoctrination of children in Communist-established summer camps. In the report, Studer was specifically "identified as a long-time member of the Communist Party." Studer was also accused of having "purposely hired Communists as his assistants at the camp." One of the possible assistants being alluded to may have been Pete Seeger, who is also identified in this report as being "Pro-Communist." Studer testified before the Committee in August 1955; however, formal charges were never filed against Studer nor Camp Woodland. When testifying, Studer invoked the Fifth Amendment when asked about Communist Party membership, answered other questions and read a prepared statement. The files include Studer's statement, subpoena, related correspondence (including hate mail sent to Studer), newsclippings, and Committee resolutions and a final report.
    There also are a small number of documents related to Camp Hilltop where Norman Studer served as director of education before helping to found Camp Woodland.
    - Administrative Notes, 1959-1961; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 1944 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - Annual Report, 1945 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - Annual Report, 1946 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Annual Report, 1947 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - Annual Report, 1948 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - Annual Report, 1949 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Annual Report, 1950 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - Annual Report, 1951 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Annual Report, 1952 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
    - Annual Report, 1953 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 11)
    - Annual Report, 1954 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 12)
    - Annual Report, 1955 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 13)
    - Annual Report, 1956 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 14)
    - Annual Report, 1957 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 15)
    - Annual Report, 1958 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 16)
    - Annual Report, 1959 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 17)
    - Area Hotel Discrimination, 1951; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 18)
    - Bibliography, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 19)
    - Board of Directors Dispute and Related Legal Materials, 1952; 1958-1963; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 20)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1954-1962; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 21)
    - Budgets, ca. 1953 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 22)
    - Camp Hilltop, 1938; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 23)
    - Camp Hilltop Brochures, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 24)
    - Camp Woodland Brochures, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 25)
    - Camp Woodland, Correspondence, 1942-1962; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 26)
    - Camp Woodland Goals and Reflections, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 27)
    - Camp Woodland Organization, ca. 1945 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 28)
    - Camp Woodland Parents Association, 1954; 1957-1961; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 29)
    - Camp Woodland's Design for Integration, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - Camper Council, 1946-1947; 1950; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - Campers List, 1953; 1955-1959; 1961-1962 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1942 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
    - Communications to the Staff, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Correspondence to Staff, No Positions Available, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - Counselor-in-Training Reports, 1949; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - Counselor-in-Training Yearbook, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Counselor's Handbook, ca. 1945 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - Deferred Salaries, 1962; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Dewey Administration Investigation of Camps, Thompkins-Rabin Joint Legislative Committee, 1954 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
    - Difficulty Advertising for Camp Woodland as a Result of Larkin Committee Investigation, 1954-1957; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 11)
    - Duties and Responsibilities, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 12)
    - Efforts to Bring Little Rock Nine to Camp Woodland, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 13)
    - End-of-Season Suggestions, Planning, Reports, 1943-1961; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 14)
    - Evaluations, 1953; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 15)
    - Executive Committee, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 16)
    - Film, 1949 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 17)
    - Fire, 1963 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 18)
    - Folklore Education at Woodland, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 19)
    - Guest Books, 1952-1956 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 20)
    - Guide for Group Leaders, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 21)
    - Hate Mail Resulting from Publicity from Larkin Committee, 1956; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 22)
    - Investigation '55, Larkin Committee, 1954-1956; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 23)
    - Larkin Committee Investigation, Concerns of Downtown Community School Parents, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 24)
    - Larkin Committee, Newsclippings, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 25)
    - Map by Joan Goldhirsch, ca. 1950 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
    - Parents Lists, 1951; 1953-1962; Undated (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - Precamp Orientation, 1951 (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - Property Dispute with Lewis Hallenbeck, 1953-1954 (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - Staff and Counselor Reflections, Undated (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1939; 1944; 1948-1949; Undated (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - Staff Roster, 1955-1956; 1959-1960; 1962 (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - Unsubstantiated Rumor about Refusing Rosenberg Children at Camp, 1954 (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Woodland Newsletter, 1941-1947 (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - Work Camp, 1948; Undated (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Youth Week, 1961; Undated (Box 3 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
  - Activities, 1940-1974; Undated; 4.2
    The Activities subseries consists primarily of publications, event announcements, writings, and art produced by campers, or counselors of Camp Woodland. Notable materials include copies of the Camp magazine, Neighbors; programs, announcements, news clippings, and correspondence related to the Folk Festival of the Catskills; ephemeral publications; and various creative writings. There also are materials about the Folk Museum.
    The publication Neighbors was originally published as the Folk Festival of the Catskills program, but eventually became a separate publication in 1944 and continued until 1962. It evolved into an annual magazine devoted to recording the explorations and discoveries of campers and camp counselors each summer. Please note that the Studer Papers do not have a complete run of Neighbors. Noted musician and composer, Norman Cazden, and occasionally Herbert Haufrecht, supervised the folk music contributions of Neighbors; as a result, it became a rich source of sheet music and lyrics for regional folksongs.
    Camp Woodland culminated each year with the annual Folk Festival of the Catskills. Studer invited many of the local fiddlers, musicians, dance callers, and ballad singers to join the campers in a folk festival performance for the counselors, community members, and parents. Studer organized the folk festival with the manifold purpose of reviving the Catskill heritage of folk music and dance. Pete Seeger periodically performed at the Folk Festival of the Catskills, particularly during the early years. Many of the festivals were recorded by Studer, and are located in Series 6: Audio Recordings and Series 7: Films. Please note that the Folk Festival of the Catskills files have different types and amounts of materials depending upon the year. Some simply have programs or a list of events. Others have this, but also feature extensive planning records, newspaper clips, analysis and speeches.
    The Folk Museum of the Catskills began with a small collection of tools representing folk life in the region. These were held at Camp Woodland, but the museum sought a more permanent home during the next two decades. The museum was first housed in the Butterfly House at Camp, then in a home on Main Street in Phoenicia, and later at the Ski House at Simpson Ski Slope. In 1957 campers began clearing land and a site at the Camp for a new museum structure. The Museum was dedicated during the 1962 Folk Festival of the Catskills. After Camp Woodland closed, Studer relocated the materials to a museum at the Downtown Community School and eventually these tools were donated to other museums and repositories. Several tools are now held at the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives. Please see the Folk Festival of the Catskills files for additional content on the museum.
    - Athletic Schedule, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - Autobiography of a Bluestone Quarry, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - Camp Diary of Nancy Kurshan, 1958 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - Camp Woodland Felt Patch, Junior Camp, ca. 1945 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Camper Writings, Articles by Campers on Sholam, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - Camper Writings, Articles from 1949 Neighbors, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - Camper Writings, Camp Life, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Camper Writings, Camper Council, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - Camper Writings, Drought and Flood, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Camper Writings, Living Things, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
    - Camper Writings, Photocopied Compilation from Various Summers, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 11)
    - Camper Writings, Poetry, 1954; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 12)
    - Camper Writings, Recollections of Catskills Residents, 1950; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 13)
    - Camper Writings, Summer Highlights, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 14)
    - Camper Writings, Tall Tales, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 15)
    - Camper Writings Thoughts: Serious and Silly, ca. 1960 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 16)
    - Camper Writings, Trips and Visits, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 17)
    - Camper Writings, Work Camp, 1957-1958; 1960; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 18)
    - Camper Writings, World Youth Week, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 19)
    - Campfire, 1946 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 20)
    - Canal Trip, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 21)
    - "The Compleat Folk Singer," by Sam Delaney, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 22)
    - Catskill Caller, 1941-1962; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 23)
    - Catskill Folklore and Oral History Collected by Campers or at Camp, 1944-1945; 1947; 1950; 1954; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 24)
    - "The Coming of the Peoples", Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 25)
    - Composer's Notebook of Catskill Folk Music, Camper Niela Miller, ca. 1948-1952 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 26)
    - Cookouts and Overnights, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 27)
    - Correspondence with Escuela Nacional de Danzas Folkloricas Argentinas, 1948 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 28)
    - "Dances From Woodland", 1945; 1955 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 29)
    - Drama at Woodland, 1947; 1954; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 30)
    - Drawings by Joan Goldhirsch-Roelof, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 31)
    - Edwards, George (See Catskill Caller for More Tributes), 1946; 1949; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 32)
    - Exhibit of Photographs of Camp Woodland by Helene Pragan, 1946 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 33)
    - "Exploration: Unearthing Local History and Folklore with the People of the Catskills," by A.A. Hartwell, 1948 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 34)
    - Farewell Banquet, 1946; 1950-1953; 1958 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 35)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 2nd Annual, 1941; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 36)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 3rd Annual, 1942 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 37)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 4th Annual, 1943 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 38)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 4th Annual, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 15)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 5th Annual, 1944; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 39)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 6th Annual, 1945 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 40)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 7th Annual, 1946 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 41)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 8th Annual, 1947; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 42)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 9th Annual, 1948 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 43)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 10th Annual, ca. 1949 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1950 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 44)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1951 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 45)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 12th Annual, ca. 1951 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1953; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 46)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 14th Annual, ca. 1953 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1954; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 47)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1955 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 48)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1956; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 49)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1957 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 50)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1958 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 51)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1959; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 52)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, ca. 1961 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 53)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, 1962 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 54)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, Nellie Bly Ballard Art Exhibit, 1960; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 55)
    - Folk Festival of the Catskills, Partial List of Dates, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 56)
    - Folk Museum, Catalogue Cover, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 57)
    - Folk Museum, Artifact Descriptions, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 58)
    - Folk Museum, Beginnings, 1953; 1959; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 59)
    - Folk Museum, Donor List, 1953 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 60)
    - Folk Museum, Flyers about Museum, 1951; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 61)
    - Folk Museum, Hoop Making, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 62)
    - Folk Museum, Inventory, 1962; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 63)
    - Folk Museum, Newsclippings, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 64)
    - Folk Museum, Newsclippings About Building and Dedication of Museum at Camp Woodland, 1960; 1962 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 65)
    - Folk Museum, Pieces Lent to Camp Thoreau, 1972 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 66)
    - Folk Museum, Programming, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 67)
    - Folk Museum, Woodland Collection, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 68)
    - Folk Museum, Woodland Collection Exhibits, 1950; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 69)
    - Gifts for the Arkville Museum, from Norman Studer, 1974 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 70)
    - Goals for Children at Camp, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 71)
    - Hiking Trips, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 72)
    - Hill Top Highlights, 1940 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 73)
    - Jones, Bessie, 1958; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 74)
    - The Junior Woodlander, 1952 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 75)
    - Maps of Trips, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 76)
    - Modern Dance, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 77)
    - Music, Writing and Photos from Loose Pages of Neighbors, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 78)
    - My Songbook, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 79)
    - Neighbors, 1946-1949 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 80)
    - Neighbors, 1950 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 81)
    - Neighbors, 1951-1953 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 82)
    - Neighbors, 1954-1958 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 83)
    - Neighbors, 1960; 1962 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 84)
    - Notebook of Nature Counselor Beulah Tannenbaum, 1950-1952 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 85)
    - Olympic Day, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 86)
    - "One Camper Remembers…", Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 87)
    - Our Catskill Neighbors, 1945 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 88)
    - Patriotism, 1942; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 89)
    - Peace on Earth, 1961 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 90)
    - Plays, "Action on Dingle Hill", 1958; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - Plays, "Boney Quillen", 1953 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - Plays, "Canalers, Canalers…by Norman Studer," Presented by the Woodland Players, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - Plays, Cantatas, and Modern Dances by Woodland Players, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Plays, "Down Rent", 1941; 1945 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - Plays, "The Lonesome Train", 1944-1945 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - Plays, "Pang Yang Poet", 1957 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Plays, "Sojourner Truth", 1953; 1962 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - Plays, "They Came to Shalom", 1960 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Plays, "The Way it Used to Be", 1954-1955; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
    - Plays, "We've Come from the City," by Herbert Haufrecht, 1945; 1948; 1956 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 11)
    - Possible Trips for Groups, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 12)
    - Poster with Images, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
    - Programs for Final Periods of Camp, 1945; 1947 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 13)
    - Report of Music at Camp Woodland, 1960 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 14)
    - Sampsonville Trips, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 15)
    - Sholam, 1957; 1972 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 16)
    - Slack, Orson, 1945-1946; 1952; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 17)
    - Smith, Ernie, Poetry, 1944; 1948; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 18)
    - "The Story of Samsonville," by Louis Sarlin, Camp Woodland, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 19)
    - Storytelling, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 20)
    - Trip to Water System, Watershed, Reservoir, 1949; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 21)
    - Trip Program, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 22)
    - Trips, General Rules and Guides, Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 23)
    - Todd, Mike, 1960; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 24)
    - Upstate Meets Downstate Folk Music Concert, 1961 April 05 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 25)
    - Visit to Malby Hollow and Jacky Brook Farm, 1962 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 26)
    - V-J Day at Camp Woodland, 1945; Undated (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 27)
    - Wood Bones Made by Mike Todd for Bobby Orlins, Junior Camp, ca. 1945 (Artifact-box 1)
    - Woodlanders at College by Matie Chalk, ca. 1957; 1962 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 28)
    - Work Camper, 1953 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 29)
    - Work Camp Courier, 1961 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 30)
    - The World is a Neighborhood, 1944-1946 (Box 2 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 31)
  - Post-Camp, 1977-2012; Undated; 4.3
    This small subseries contains materials documenting Camp Woodland related activities and events which occurred after the camp closed. This includes reunions and the creation of The Woodland Sampler, a compilation of Catskill folk music played at Camp Woodland, including some recordings from the annual Folk Festival of the Catskills. Norman Studer embarked on the The Woodland Sampler project in 1977, a year before his death, and it was continued by his family, including daughter Joan Studer Levine and grandson Eric Levine. The Levines published a cassette and an accompanying booklet detailing the songs, poetry and music on the tape in 1987.
    - 1997 Camp Woodland Reunion Administrative Materials, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 1)
    - 1997 Camp Woodland Reunion Photographs, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 2)
    - 1997 Camp Woodland Reunion Registration Forms and Roster, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 3)
    - 1997 Camp Woodland Reunion Survey and Follow-up, 2002 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 4)
    - Botkin Celebration, Library of Congress, 2001 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 5)
    - "Camp Woodland: Progressive Education and Folklore in the Catskill Mountains of New York State," by Dale Johnson, 2002 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 6)
    - California Reunion of Larry Spellens, Danny Braunstein, Eddie Barad, Bobby Orlins, 2002 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 7)
    - Camp Woodland Reunion Alumni List, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 8)
    - List of Folk Songs Compiled by Carolyn (Kopperl) Bensinger, Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 9)
    - Map, Camp Woodland, Drawn by Robert "Bobby" Orlins, 2012 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 10)
    - Memorial to Herbert Haufrecht, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 11)
    - New York Folk Love Society Grant Application, 2001; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 12)
    - Woodland Letter and List, 2001; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 13)
    - The Woodland Sampler, 1987; 2001; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 14)
    - The Woodland Sampler Permissions, 1977-1980; 1983-1985; 1987-1989; Undated (Box 1 (4-Camp Woodland), Folder 15)
- Photographs, ca. 1934-ca. 1970; Undated; 5; 3.21 cubic ft.
  Unless noted, this series contains photographs and postcards taken, collected by or featuring Norman Studer. There are images from the Little Red School House, Elisabeth Irwin High School, Downtown Community School, Camp Woodland, family trips out-of-state, and various New York locations. While archivists, Studer family members and former students and campers have made identifications where possible, the majority of the photographs contain unidentified individuals or events and are undated.
  - School Photographs, ca. 1934-ca.1970; Undated; 5.1
    The School photographs subseries contains images of children's activities, classes, field trips, special guests, including Red Thunder Cloud, and performances. The bulk of the photographs are from the Downtown Community School, but there are some images from the Little Red School House and Elisabeth Irwin High School.